<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Filipe Ximenes</title><link href="http://filipeximenes.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://filipeximenes.github.io/feeds/tag/web.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://filipeximenes.github.io/</id><updated>2014-02-04T17:00:00-03:00</updated><entry><title>URL's, URI's and URN's</title><link href="http://filipeximenes.github.io/urls-uris-urns.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-04T17:00:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Filipe Ximenes</name></author><id>tag:filipeximenes.github.io,2014-02-04:urls-uris-urns.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_resource_locator"&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_resource_identifier"&gt;URI&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_resource_name"&gt;URN&lt;/a&gt; are widely used terms when we talk about the web, althought they seem to be the same, they are actualy not. There is a slitght diference between each one of them. Let's take a look at URI's first.
According to wikipedia URI's are:   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;"a uniform resource identifier (URI) is a string of characters used to identify a name of a web resource"&lt;/code&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to understanding is &lt;code&gt;a string of characters&lt;/code&gt;, URI's are a concept of how to identify things on the web.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to identify something, for instance, you can use a name, a location or even a descrition of the object. In the web it works just the same, you can identify resourses by name or by it's location. To each identification method we have a name: URN (Uniform Resourse Name) and URL (Uniform Resource Location).   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how does each of this look like in real world? Lets say I want to refer to the book "Rework" I can do this using the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number"&gt;ISBN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/URI_scheme"&gt;scheme&lt;/a&gt; URN: &lt;code&gt;isbn: 0307463745&lt;/code&gt;, which will identify the exact book I'm taking about or in case I want to tell you about where to buy it, I can point to the HTTP &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/URI_scheme"&gt;scheme&lt;/a&gt; URL: &lt;code&gt;http://www.amazon.com/Rework-Jason-Fried/dp/0307463745&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="web"></category></entry></feed>